# **Charles Danner**

Fort Mill, SC, 29708

Phone: (864) 993-5071 | Email: danner.ced1@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/charles-danner-9a020918a/

GitHub: https://github.com/charlesdanner | Portfolio: https://charlesdanner.github.io/myPortfolio/

## Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a desire to continuously learn, improve and to be engaged with a rewarding and successful career. Experienced with team oriented projects, creative problem solving and mobile first web applications. Recognized for hard work, attention to detail and being an excellent team contributor.

### **Technical Skills**

**Languages:** Proficiency in the core languages used in Front End Web Development. A deep understanding of HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Also has experience working with JSX in React.js.

**Libraries/Frameworks:** Understands how to utilize libraries and frameworks that can speed up the development process for many different types of web based applications. Experienced and knowledgeable of Twitter Bootstrap, Express.js and React.js.

**Technologies:** Experience working with various different integral technologies relating to Full Stack Web Development. These technologies consist of databases, ORMs, HTML template engines and web based technology used for other various purposes. These include but are not limited to Git, TSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, Firebase, Visual Studio Code, React.js and Axios.

# **Projects**

Name: The Grid

**GitHub:** https://github.com/charlesdanner/Project-3

Link: <a href="https://the-grid.herokuapp.com/">httphttps://the-grid.herokuapp.com/</a>

**Summary:** A React Single Page Application designed to be a social media platform built around video game players and their need to network, communicate and organize. Users have their own accounts, can join Clans, add friends make posts and comment on other people's posts.

**Responsibilities:** Researched and implemented various React.js imports such as useContext, Hooks and Media Helmet. Mainly responsible for work with ORMs,

Tools/Languages: HTML, JSX, CSS, JavaScript, Axios, Node.js, Express.js, React.js,

MongoDB, Mongoose, BootStrap, BCRYPT, JSON Web Token.

Name: Next Game

**GitHub:** https://github.com/charlesdanner/Thundercats

**Link:** https://shawngway.github.io/Thundercats/

**Summary:** A web-based application that utilizes third party APIs in order for users to research different video games they're interested in, add games to a wishlist and browse games similar to what they already enjoy.

**Responsibilities:** Responsible for the front-end JavaScript. This includes user login validation, DOM manipulation, wiring up HTTP GET requests, and ensuring the data relating to user statistics was persistent.

Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Axios, Firebase, Rawg.io API and IGDB

API

Name: Crop Circle

**GitHub:** https://github.com/charlesdanner/project2 **Link:** https://project2-cropcircle.herokuapp.com/

**Summary:** An online forum for users to discuss various topics that they are interested in. Similar to Reddit in that users can create new topics based on different URL endpoints. Users have their own accounts and can view post history, comment history and favorite different categories.

**Responsibilities:** Responsible for the front-end JavaScript, user validation and creation, creating the various schemas used in the database, manipulating the DOM based on whether the user was logged in and restricting access to specific URL endpoints based on whether the user is logged in or not.

**Tools/Languages:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Axios, Node.js, Express.js, Express-Handlebars, Sequelize, BootStrap and JSON Web Token

## **Work History**

Delivery Driver	Marco's Pizza	2018-present
Sales Consultant	Palmetto Roofing & Exteriors	2017-2018
Sales Associate	Walgreens	2013-2017

#### Education

**Bootcamp Certificate:** University of North Carolina Charlotte, Charlotte, NC (Graduation date: 01/11/2019) A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.